<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Interferometer xmlns="https://openinterferometry.org/schema/aios/1.1"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="https://openinterferometry.org/schema/aios/1.1 aios-interferometer-v1.1.xsd"
  schemaVersion="1.1.0">

  <identity>
    <id>22222222-2222-2222-2222-222222222222</id>
    <shortName>Bhardwaj-2024-SingleLaser-Fountain-Gravimeter</shortName>
    <description>
      Paper-based metadata example derived from Bhardwaj et al. (arXiv:2405.04223, 2024).
      This is a stationary laboratory cold-atom gravimeter in fountain geometry, using Doppler-sensitive
      two-photon Raman pulse atom interferometry. Values included here are those explicitly stated in the paper HTML.
    </description>
    <manufacturer>In-house developed (RRCAT)</manufacturer>
    <model>Cold Atom Gravimeter (CAG) - single laser operated fountain</model>
    <buildDate>2024-05-07</buildDate>
  </identity>

  <apparatus>
    <atomicSource>
      <species>Rb87</species>
      <isotopeDetail>Laser cooled 87Rb launched vertically in atomic fountain geometry</isotopeDetail>
      <sourceType>Atomic fountain (single-laser operated)</sourceType>
      <notes>
        Paper describes use of Doppler-sensitive two-photon Raman excitation and internal-state atom interferometry.
        It also states the system was operated without seismic vibration corrections during the reported measurements.
      </notes>
    </atomicSource>

    <pulseSequence>
      <topology>MachZehnder_3Pulse</topology>
      <beamType>Raman</beamType>
      <notes>Raman pulse atom interferometry for g measurement in fountain geometry.</notes>
    </pulseSequence>
  </apparatus>

  <performance>
    <measurand>Local gravitational acceleration (g)</measurand>
    <accuracy>
      <value>9.786173</value>
      <unit>m/s^2</unit>
      <note>Reported local g value (laboratory) in the paper HTML.</note>
    </accuracy>
    <sensitivity>
      <value>621</value>
      <unit>uGal</unit>
      <note>Allan deviation / sensitivity for 1350 s integration time, as reported.</note>
    </sensitivity>
    <notes>
      Paper also reports a resolution of 270 uGal for the g estimate obtained from the Raman chirp method.
    </notes>
  </performance>

  <provenance>
    <references>
      <reference>
        <title>Measurement of gravitational acceleration in a single laser operated atomic fountain</title>
        <authors>Kavish Bhardwaj et al.</authors>
        <year>2024</year>
        <arxiv>2405.04223</arxiv>
        <uri>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.04223</uri>
      </reference>
      <reference>
        <title>HTML version: Measurement of gravitational acceleration in a single laser operated atomic fountain</title>
        <authors>Kavish Bhardwaj et al.</authors>
        <year>2024</year>
        <uri>https://arxiv.org/html/2405.04223v1</uri>
      </reference>
    </references>
    <citation>Bhardwaj, K. et al. (2024). Measurement of gravitational acceleration in a single laser operated atomic fountain. arXiv:2405.04223.</citation>
  </provenance>

</Interferometer>
